## MARCUS HUDNELL

Full-Stack Software Engineer

(561) 389.6421 · hudnell.marcus@gmail.com · Los Angeles, CA · <u>linkedin.com/in/marcus-hudnell/</u> · <u>github.com/hudnellmarcus</u>

I am a full-stack engineer with a passion for solving problems and implementing solutions aimed at efficiency. With 10+ years in the workforce and experience on sales teams as well as client-facing operations, communication and teamwork are two of my most valuable skills. Proven adaptability and an eagerness to learn make me an ideal

#### **SKILLS**

addition to any team.

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - MERN stack, Python, Django Integration and Testing: Mocha, Chai, Docker, Jenkins | Database - PostgreSQL, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM |

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

April 2022 - Present

#### **TeeTime**

- A MERN stack, full CRUD web application that allows users to register, login and track their tee times at various golf courses and makes use of RESTful routing and REST API's.
- Programmed user authentication and authorization fully implemented using Google Firebase.
- Front-End developed with ReactJS, CSS and Materialize library.
- Back-End development utilizing Express framework to maintain server and MongoDB to store user data.
- Automated tests using Mocha test framework and Chai library.
- Containerized using Docker and connected to build pipeline through Jenkins integration.

#### **Festivalist**

- Created a full CRUD web application developed using the Django framework for Python.
- Allows users to register, login, and add/update music events they are attending.
- Styled using Materialize and custom CSS.
- Utilizes MVT architecture along with an SQL database for storing data managed by PostgreSQL

#### **OddsMakers**

- Prompt: Design a tool that displays betting odds for sports leagues around the world. The application aggregates betting lines and props from 12 major sportsbooks. The goal was to provide a tool that would allow bettors to compare the best odds being given across different betting platforms.
- Utilized front-end technologies including: Javascript, HTML, CSS as well as the Jquery library and AJAX component to access API data.
- Created application with a mobile-first approach and styled the application using Styled-Components and CSS3
  with flexgrid and flexbox layouts.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cardinal Financial Company, Mortgage Loan Originator I Remote

**February 2021 - March 2022** 

- Completed mortgage applications for submission to the loan processing and underwriting departments.
- Communicated with applicants and/or referral sources by providing timely updates and progress reports.

- Secured referral contacts (realtors, builders, professional and personal contacts).
- Compiled a database of qualified leads through referrals, telephone canvassing, face to face cold-calling, direct mail, email and networking.
- Knowledge of federal lending regulations governing real estate lending and the the lending process including: processing, underwriting and all relevant guidelines
- Targeted sales calls at potential or existing customers as established in marketing plan to develop new business or retain existing business.

# National Debt Relief, Sales Representative/Debt Specialist I Los Angeles, CA July 2017 - August 2020

In the sales rep role at NDR I consulted and aided consumers in taking advantage of life-changing financial assistance through debt relief programs.

- Worked with clients to assess their financial situation and develop customized solutions.
- Strategically implemented methods to increase team member productivity and limit client cancellation rates.
- Promoted to co-captain in June of 2018
- Client retention rate of 81% over my tenure at the company currently.
- · Hit monthly sales milestone for 8 months consecutively

## SMARTer Bodies, Personal Trainer, Blog Contributor, Social Media Management I New York, NY December 2013 - February 2018

- Through Smarter Bodies I gained invaluable experience in freelancing, as well as experiencing what it takes to build and promote a business/brand at its roots.
- Worked remote as well as in person to complete tasks and collaborate with team members.
- Have written two well-received articles, which showcased my aptitude for meticulous research, and careful analysis of topics that I deemed important in the fitness community.
- Assisted in improving audience engagement, and driving the growth of our community through the use of social media platforms such as: Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter.
- Constantly worked with the other members of the 'Smarter Bodies' team to brainstorm ways of increasing our reach, and take the brand to the next level.

### **EDUCATION**

## **GENERAL ASSEMBLY I REMOTE**

Software Engineering Immersive

May 2021 - July 2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

### **COLGATE UNIVERSITY I HAMILTON, NEW YORK**

Bachelor of Arts in (Geography), (English Literature)

June 2007 - May 2011